Anthony Alaribe

Berlin, Berlin, Germany

anthonyalaribe@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/anthony-alaribe-293a41bb

Summary

Over the years as a Software Engineer, my focus has been on blurring the line between security and performance in the software I help design or develop. The idea is not to mindlessly churning out code, but to consider about the short and long term implications of each technical decision, while keeping the business goals in mind.

Experience

Co-Founder

APItoolkit

Sep 2021 - Present (2 years 7 months)

I co-founded APItoolkit based off challenges I and colleagues had to deal with in previous jobs. Regressions and bugs are just way too common in modern software, and we want to change that.

Engineering Lead

Talstack

Nov 2023 - Present (5 months)

Building and Leading the GTM of the Talstack Talent management and upskilling platform

Common Good Parachains Engineer

Parity Technologies

Aug 2022 - Jul 2023 (1 year)

Work on building cross chain experiences on the polkadot network, especially between Polkadot and Statemint. Lead the effort towards implementing a Multi-Asset Treasury

Staff Software Engineer

Delivery Hero

Jul 2021 - Jul 2022 (1 year 1 month)

Senior Software Engineer

Delivery Hero

Jan 2020 - Jul 2021 (1 year 7 months)

I was part of starting the Location Intelligence team, where we built a service for performing geocoding services as well as being the go to service for all polygon management and point in polygon usecases in the company, as well the exploration of a DH maps service which uses a machine learning model to perform geocoding workloads using only our existing order data. (coordinates and addresses), in certain markets where we had high order density. This opened room for a lot of optimization tasks.

I also still run the Golang guild in Delivery Hero, organizing meetups, workshops and trainings, and also mentoring teams who are switching to using Golang for their services.

Software Engineer

Delivery Hero

Jan 2019 - Jan 2020 (1 year 1 month)

I worked on the team responsible for the search and listing experiences, leading the migration of the legacy service from PHP to Golang. We went from barely being able to handle a 100k requests per minute, to handling over a million requests per minute within a little over a year.

I also ran the Golang Guild within the company, organizing internal meetups, trainings and events to help improve the general golang skill level and experience in the company, while also giving new golang engineers a platform to get support, share learnings, etc within the company.

I improved our geocoding service that building an inmemory geospatial cache on top of. an rtree, after implementing and benchmarking multiple solutions. The result of this exploration was that our cities by coordinate endpoints went down in response time from >30ms to less than 1ms. We were also able to handle 9x our maximum traffic for this service with the same server resources.

Software Developer

Opera

Mar 2018 - Oct 2018 (8 months)

I worked with the Opay team, building Opay, which is a fin-tech product. I led the integration of Opay into the Nigerian Interbank Settlement System (NIBSS), in a bid to reduce our transaction failure rates from using third parties.

I also led the development of a system for setting and managing fees set on different products within the Opay application, with a lot of emphasis on an audit log for tracking changes to fees on the products in Opay.

Software Engineer

Informant Technologies

Feb 2017 - Feb 2018 (1 year 1 month)

Informant Technologies is a philadelphia based public safety and law enforcement technologies provider. I was part of the team building technoloies to be used by the US police, especially around managing and sharing their huge stores of case data. I also lead development of an enterprise role based data management system for multinationals like LTK.com (Responsible for North America's rail system).

Technical Team Lead

Aug 2016 - Jun 2017 (11 months)

DoneHire Global is a Company based in San Jose California. The company provides an innovative social approach to recruiting, with clients including large global companies such as Synaptics. I was technical cofounder, and worked to help launch Donehire.

Technical Lead

Kaku

2014 - 2015 (1 year)

I lead developing the user facing platform: frontend and backend in the Go programming language which was just getting traction then.

https://techcabal.com/2015/04/03/kaku-the-discovery-website-is-now-live/

Education



🔷 University of Calabar

Bachelor of Medical Laboratory Science, Clinical/Medical Laboratory Science/ Research and Allied Professions

2011 - 2016

My team came second in the NASA space apps challenge in Calabar.

Skills

HTMX • Leading Development Teams • IT Leadership • Web Services • Haskell • Observability • System Monitoring • Time Series Analysis • Documentation • Machine Learning

Honors & Awards

NASA space apps challenge (Cross River State)

Feb 2015

My team came second in the NASA space apps challenge in Cross River State, which was held at the IDEA hub. We created an app that lets anyone control a computer from anywhere in the world, with just their cell phone. The cell phone uses its touch screen to emulate a mouse and keyboard, while also supporting launching applications on the computer with just voice commands.